### ARMANDO GONZALEZ

Atlanta, GA • U.S. Citizen armandogonz14@gatech.edu • https://agonz97.github.io/

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Armando Gonzalez is a passionate, personable team player, with early experience in software development and an intense interest for developing products centered on an intuitive, clear, and capable user experience. In his free time, he enjoys free writing and making art of many forms – from narrative poetry, to pixel drawings and small video games.

### **EDUCATION**

# GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, College of Computing

Atlanta, Georgia

May 2020

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** Concentration in Media and People

### **SKILLS**

Technical: Proficiency in Java, Golang, Python, Elasticsearch, AWS;

Familiarity with C, Android Development, AngularJS, Sql, Shell Scripting

Proficiency in Object Oriented Programming, Restful Web Services, Service Development; **Application:** 

Familiarity with Aspect Oriented Programming, Application Development, Game Development

Running and Planning Events, Organization and Leadership of Groups, Project Management Leadership:

Public Speaking (Presentational, Interpersonal, and Written), Group Mediation and Problem Solving **Communication:** 

### **PROJECTS**

# GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

### VIP Research Program

Fall 2016 - Spring 2018

- Developed a database-backed, live map with JS utilized by managers of Georgia Tech's bus system
- Collected data on bus system behavior using an Android application and Estimote beacons

### **Android Application Development**

*Spring 2017* 

- Developed an application in class that allows users to submit and view water reports in the area
- Application backed by a live database and uses a live updated Google map

## **Gameboy Advance Game Development**

Spring 2018

- Created a game for the Gameboy Advance called Bit-a-Fish
- Wrote the entirety of the game code in C
- Created original art for the game's sprites

#### MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL, ADVANCED MEDIA

Wrote a script to check the health of various app deployments in real time Summer 2016 Implemented a powerful, free-form, and text-based search engine for a web-based application Summer 2016 Performed an extensive backfill of media data using Amazon Web Services Summer 2017

#### **PATIENTCO**

Rebuilt a search engine to improve its speed, accuracy, and flexibility when searching patient data Fall 2017 Wrote an internal tool/service that used OCR to read images and searched for associated information Summer 2018

# **EXPERIENCE**

### MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL, ADVANCED MEDIA

New York, New York

New York, New York

Summer 2016

- Software Engineering Intern, Multimedia Development Team Shortly graduated from small projects to full-stack applications
- Actively participated on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Scrum)
- Projects required exposure to all major touch points of MLBAM's technical ecosystem
- Delivered several formal demos and presentations to other interns and members of the Engineering Department

# **BAMTECH LLC (formerly MLBAM)**

### Software Engineering Intern, Multimedia Development Team

Summer 2017

- Worked as an independent, full-stack engineer in a fast-paced environment
- Developed production level software on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Scrum)
- Participated in a department-wide Hackathon that exposed me to other teams within Engineering

**PATIENTCO** Atlanta, Georgia Fall 2017

### Software Engineering Coop, Platform Team

Individually developed a net-new service and designed a search cluster using Elasticsearch and Golang

- Developed production level software on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Kanban)
- Participated in a career fair and other follow-up recruiting efforts on behalf of the company
- Delivered a formal demo and presentation to other members of the Engineering Department and C.S.O.

# Lead Software Engineering Coop, Platform Team

Summer 2018

- Performed as lead developer on another net-new service with cross-departmental stakeholders
- Managed an internal project using Agile Software (Kanban) Methods and taught these methods to others
- Delivered several formal demos and presentation to other members of the Engineering Department, and Customer Support
- Discovered a major security and compliance vulnerability in one of our vendors' websites

### **LEADERSHIP**

# GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Georgia Tech Spirit Program, Spirit Leader

Atlanta, Georgia

Fall 2017 – Present

- Represents Georgia Tech on local, state, and national level as an ambassador and symbol for Georgia Tech
- Maintain strict fitness and diet regimen, training daily while balancing school and extracurricular activities
- Commit an average of 10 hours per week towards attending on and off campus events with high energy and enthusiasm

## New Student and Sophomore Programs, Orientation Director of Staff Development

Fall 2017 – Present

- Led a staff of 40 through weekly trainings focused on group mediation and leadership •
- Attended the Southern Regional Orientation Workshop to learn more about leadership and group management
- Helped plan a three-day, extended orientation camp to help transition incoming Georgia Tech students

### New Student and Sophomore Programs, Orientation Leader

Spring 2016 - Fall 2017

- Co-led a small group of students as a part of an extended orientation program
- Joined a staff of 30+ students focused on community building and transitioning into life at Georgia Tech